我是兰姆
This is Lamb.
如果我没接电话 那是因为我不想跟你说话
If I didn't answer, it's because I don't want to speak to you.
喂 骗到你了吧 我是马库斯·朗里奇 请留言
Hello. Got you, didn't I? It's Marcus Longridge. Leave a message.
给 慢用 谢谢
Here you go. Enjoy. Cheers.
我是瑞弗 请留言
This is River. Leave a message.
喂
Hello?
终于有人接电话了
Finally. Someone picked up.
你在哪
Where are you?
关你屁事
None of your business.
好吧 你应该来鸡多多快餐的
Yeah, well, you're supposed to be at the Chickado.
为什么
Why?
我们的圣诞派对啊
Our Christmas party.
我们没有圣诞派对
We don't have a Christmas party.
如果有 那也是在圣诞节前开 而且不会在鸡多多快餐
And if we did, we'd have it before Christmas and not at a Chickado.
好吧 也许你没被邀请
Yeah. Well, maybe you're not invited.
也许兰姆只跟精英说了
Maybe Lamb only told the elites.
可兰姆跟你说了 对吧
Lamb told you about it though, didn't he?
我问他圣诞派对在哪开 他就把细节告诉我了
I asked him where the Christmas party was, and he gave me the details.
是啊
Right.
你想想看是怎么回事吧
See if you can work out what happened.
好吧 也得是局内人才会被耍 所以
Yeah, well, you gotta be in the game to get played, so...
喂
Hello?
在韦斯特艾克斯购物中心
At Westacres shopping center.
确认 是汽车炸弹
Confirmed there's a car bomb.
(韦斯特艾克斯)
局长来了
First Desk approaching.
我是克劳德·惠兰局长
Claude Whelan, First Desk.
你是 特工辛格
And you are? Agent Singh.
好 长官
Right. Ma'am.
这种事 没法形容
I mean, something like this, there are-There are no words.
真是
It's just...
我们确认了是汽车炸弹
We're confirmed it's a car bomb?
是 长官 监控拍到了
Yes, ma'am. We have it on CCTV.
司机在车上 所以是自杀式袭击
Driver was in the car, so it was a suicide attack.
袭击购物中心 老天啊
On a shopping center. My God.
汽车驶过步行区
Car drives up through the pedestrianized area,
人群四散
people scatter,
他直接驶进入口 然后引爆
he drives straight into the entrance and detonates.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
有那辆车的信息吗
What do we know about the car?
是以罗伯特·温特斯的名字租的 28岁的自由职业IT顾问
Hired under the name Robert Winters, 28-year-old freelance IT consultant,
但从他的背景中看不出他这么干的原因
but nothing in his background to indicate why he did this.
用监控查他的行踪 我们必须知道他从哪来的
Track his journey on CCTV. We need to know where he came from.
我们查了他给租车公司的地址 位于莱斯特
We checked the address in Leicester he gave to the hire-car company.
那里已经很多年没人住了
Nobody's been there in years.
邻居们从没见过或听说过温特斯
Neighbors have never seen nor heard of Winters.
天啊
Jesus.
也许他是个幽灵人
So maybe he's a ghost.
有可能 这也许是一次性袭击事件
Could be this is a one-off.
也可能是某件事的开端
Or the start of something.
我们访问了一些伦敦人
And from talking to people in London, it seems
似乎整个社区依然很焦虑
that a sense of anxiety remains across the community.
在最新一次行动里 武装警察进驻部分地铁列车
In the latest move, armed police have been placed on some trains,
虽然这更像是增加自信的举措
although this feels more of a confidence-boosting measure
而不是针对某一特定威胁的应对
than a response to a specific threat.
你真的认为他从属于一个组织吗
Do you really think he is part of a network?
我想下一次袭击间隔越久
I guess the longer it goes without another attack,
他越可能是独狼吧
the more likely he's just a lone wolf.
我讨厌“独狼”这个词 让他显得很神秘
I hate the term "lone wolf." Makes him sound edgy.
他只是个杀人的混蛋
He's just a murderous prick.
对 我们重新敬酒
Right. We'll do that again.
我们刚刚向一个 杀人的混蛋敬酒 说点别的
We just toasted a murderous prick. Say something else.
祝我们明年这个时候不在斯劳部门了
To not being in Slough House this time next year.
好 不太可能
Yeah. That's unlikely.
除非我们辞职
Unless we just quit.
你其实不想辞职
You don't actually wanna do that,
对吧
do you?
其实吧 我一直想辞职 真的
Well, I'm always thinking about it. Yeah.
太好了
Great.
总之呢 有件事
Anyway, yeah, there's just been something
我一直想跟你说 就是
that I've wanted to share with you for a while, and, you know,
我想在办公室之外说 好吧
I wanted to do it outside of the office... Okay.
我觉得我可以跟你说
...and I've felt like I could share that with you
因为我们 我觉得我们的关系更亲近了
'cause we've-I think we've gotten closer.
是的 所以
Uh-huh. And...
我不想越界什么的
I don't want to overstep the mark or anything,
如果你想保持我们之间的工作关系 我完全理解
and I get it if you want to keep it to work when it comes to us.
瑞弗 抱歉 就是
Oh, River. I'm sorry. Just--
我是喜欢你 但 但我爷爷
I do like you, but-But my grandfather--
什么 不 你爷爷 说吧
What? No, your grandfather. Yeah.
是 你刚才说什么
Yeah, what did you just say?
我没 没什么 你继续 你以为我要说什么
I didn't-No. Go on. Carry on. What did you think I was gonna say?
你以为我要约你出去 才不是
Did you think I was gonna ask you out? No, I didn't.
你就是 不是 好吧 我是
Yes, you did. Yeah, you did. I didn't. Okay, I did.
但那是因为你要求午餐时出来喝酒
But that's because you asked for a drink at lunchtime
想跟我说一件事
'cause you wanted to talk to me about something,
然后你啰哩啰嗦说什么感觉
and then you started whanging on about how close
我们更亲近了 是 啰哩啰嗦
you felt to me and then-Yeah. Whanging on?
是真的 我感觉跟你更亲近了 现在能说你爷爷的事了吗
Well, I do. I feel closer to you. Can we go on to your grandfather now?
好
Okay.
我觉得他越来越 越来越什么
I think he's going-Going where?
就是
Like...
他总是犯糊涂
He's just confused all the time.
什么都记不住
Forgets everything.
上了年纪的人不都是这样吗
Isn't that just part of aging?
他得有80多岁了吧 不
He's like, what, 80-something? No, no.
他认为自己被“白鼬”监视
He thinks he's being watched by stoats.
白鼬是什么
What are stoats?
他那一代人对监视特工的叫法
It's what his generation call watchers.
他现在睡觉时床头放一支枪
He's sleeping with a gun by the bed.
就是
Like...
你觉得他是不是应该进敬老院
Do you think that maybe he should be in a home?
是 我觉得应该 但怎么跟他说啊
Yeah. Yeah, I do. But do you wanna tell him that?
上次我见他 他基本上头十分钟
You know, the last time I saw him, he genuinely didn't know who I was
根本认不出我
for, like, the first ten minutes.
完全不认识
No idea.
不停地跟我说他孙子瑞弗的事 我不能
He kept telling me about his grandson River. I can't--
看他这样我太难受了
It's horrible to see it.
确实不幸
Well, tough shit.
什么 是他把你带大的
What? He is the one that raised you.
没人管你时 是他照顾你
He is the one that looked after you when no one else did.
现在轮到你照顾他了
So now it's your turn.
你必须去看看他 今晚就去
You need to go and see him. Tonight.
不是 我知道 对 我知道
No, I know, I know. Yeah, I know. Yeah.
我只是需要听你对我说这些话
I just needed you to tell me that.
我知道你在 出来吧 让我看看你 来啊
I know you're there. Come on. Let me see you. Come on.
出来啊
Come on!
出来吧 我知道你在 来啊
Come on. I know you're there. Come on.
让我看看你
Let me see you.
出来吧
Come on!
瑞弗
Oh, River.
能让我进去吗 我浑身湿透了
Can you let me in? I'm getting soaked.
当然
Yes, of course.
进来
Come in.
你怎么不打电话提前说一声 还是说你打了
Why didn't you call? Or maybe you did.
我打了 但你没接 我要用下厕所
I did call you, but you didn't answer. I'm just gonna run up to the loo.
交通糟透了 这样吧 我既然都上楼了 给你放一缸洗澡水如何
Traffic was awful. And I'll tell you what, shall I run you a bath while I'm up there?
看起来你也淋雨了
Looks like you got caught in the rain too.
太难受了
It's just awful.
就快好了 爷
Almost ready, Gramps.
你不是我孙子
You're not my grandson.
别开枪 是我 瑞弗啊
Whoa. It's me. It's River.
拜托 请把枪放下好吗
C-Please. Can you put the gun down please?
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 我干了些什么
Oh, my God. What have I done?
(根据米克·赫伦的著作《惊魂街》改编)
该死
Fuck.
我是兰姆
Lamb.
见鬼
Fuck.
我进一步了解情况后打给你
I'll call you when I've got more info.
他们在勘查现场 但是 他刚到
They were going through stuff, but-He's just arrived.
我回头给你回电话
I'll call you back.
你是兰姆
You're Lamb?
这么晚了 我还惨遭质疑
This time of night, I'm plagued by doubts.
我叫艾玛·弗莱特 接替达菲的人
I'm Emma Flyte. Duffy's replacement.
一看就比达菲强
Well, you're already an improvement.
我指的是你不是脑残 也没有昏迷不醒
On account of not being brain-dead and in a coma.
小道消息说是你手下人导致他昏迷的
The grapevine says it was one of yours put him in that coma.
小道消息说什么的都有 但大多数不靠谱
Well, the grapevine says a lot of things, but it's mostly the wine talking.
达菲之前那位可厉害多了
The guy before Duffy was altogether classier.
坏人山姆·查普曼
Bad Sam Chapman.
只是个绰号而已
That was just a name.
没那么坏
Wasn't that bad.
除了弄丢两亿五千万英镑这一点
Except for that bit about losing a quarter of a billion pounds.
我说他还不坏
Well, I said he wasn't bad.
没说他完美无缺
Didn't say he was perfect.
带我看看犯罪现场吧
Want to show me the damage?
你认识卡特怀特先生
You know Mr. Cartwright?
我有不在场证明 我当时在和戴女士蒸桑拿
I have an alibi, I was in a sauna with Lady Di.
你可以问她
You can ask her.
你认识卡特怀特先生
Do you know Mr. Cartwright?
哪个 随便 两个
Which one? Either. Both.
年轻那个是我的手下
Well, the younger one works for me.
爷爷曾给过我一份工作
The grandfather gave me a job once.
鞋不错啊
They're nice shoes.
你有服装补贴
You get a clothing allowance?
该死
Fucking hell.
准备好了
You ready?
所以你是那些弃子的负责人
So, you're in charge of the rejects.
他们不喜欢被称为弃子
They don't like being called that.
那你怎么叫他们 弃子
What do you call them? The rejects.
这里 亲爱的 看 你漏掉了一点
Here, love, look. You missed a bit.
里面惨不忍睹
It's bad in there.
我见过惨的
I've seen bad before.
有人在21点03分按下了应急按钮
Someone pressed the panic button at 2103.
本地警察21点49分抵达
Local police arrived 2149.
出警可真快 还好不是紧急情况
It's a good job it wasn't an emergency.
老人家上周按下过两次按钮
The old man pressed the button twice the week before.
一次是因为他忘了按钮的用途 想按下去看看
Once because he'd forgotten what it was for and wanted to find out.
应急按钮是可追踪的 有人提到吗
Those panic buttons are traceable, anyone mention that?
谢了 我会写个注释
Thanks. I'll make a note.
但我已经追踪到他这个了 在厨房餐桌上
But I've already traced his particular button to the kitchen table.
你看了按钮下面吗
Did you look underneath it?
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
我可舒适泡腾片
Alka-Seltzer.
我平常不喝酒 但我晚餐前喝了雪利酒
Not normally a drinker, but I had a sherry before dinner.
这是犯罪现场 不是药房
This is a crime scene, not a chemist's.
他中了两枪 一枪胸口 一枪正脸
He was shot twice. Once in the chest, once in the face.
似乎有些过分
Seems excessive.
虽然他有时挺烦人的 这我承认
Though he could be annoying, I'll give you that.
你似乎不太关心啊
You don't seem too concerned.
我之前也损失过特工 你以前是一线特工
I've lost joes before. You were an active.
对 那时你还穿纸尿裤呢
Yeah, when you were still in mittens.
他当时身上带着这个
He was carrying this.
手机和钱包 都是卡特怀特的
Phone and wallet? Both Cartwright's.
那你找我干什么
What the fuck do you need me for then?
正式确认身份
Formal identification.
这可有点难
It's a bit of a challenge.
他身上有特别的记号吗
Well, did he have any identifying marks?
他本来是有脸的 有用吗
He used to have a face. That any help?
文身 伤疤 穿孔饰品 我怎么知道
Tattoos, scars, piercings? Now, how the fuck would I know?
我要求他们上班时得穿衣服
I make 'em wear clothes around the office.
是他吗
Is it him?
对 是他
Yeah, it's him.
你确定
You're sure?
是瑞弗·卡特怀特
It's River Cartwright.
那他在哪 谁在哪
So, where is he then? Where's who?
那个老不死的
The old bastard.
我们以前就这么叫他
That's what we used to call him.
他真的是个混蛋 我可以保证
And he was a bastard. I can guarantee that.
我们不知道
We have no idea.
我猜你想低调处理此事 毕竟韦斯特艾克斯刚出事
I imagine you wanna keep this quiet, what with Westacres.
韦斯特艾克斯和此事有什么关系
What does Westacres have to do with this?
没什么
Nothing.
但炸弹在伦敦爆炸 这是情报处掉链子
But a bomb goes off in London, it's an Intelligence Service fuckup,
很讽刺 恰好我们这位 小卡特怀特也是个废物
which ironically describes our young Cartwright.
如果此事公开 网上那些键盘侠一定会误会
When this gets out, the keyboard nutters will be joining the wrong dots.
公开前我们就能调查完毕
We'll wrap it up before it comes to that.
接下来的声音是我在表达自信
Well, the next sound you hear will be me expressing confidence.
厉害了
Impressive.
你能想放就放
Can you do that to order?
怎么 想再听一声
Why? Do you want another?
你真是既恶心又失礼
You are gross and inappropriate.
我正伤心难过呢 表达方式欠妥罢了
I'm working through my grief. It comes out in off ways.
你知道老卡特怀特可能去哪了吗
Any idea where Cartwright senior might go?
不知道 我回去继续睡觉了
No. I'm going back to bed.
你不考虑洗个澡吗
Would you also consider a shower?
好啊 这个提议很诱人
Yeah, it's a tempting offer,
但我觉得现在不合适
but I don't think that's appropriate right now.
毕竟抛开其他事不谈 我的一位队员刚刚死掉
I mean, apart from anything else, one of my team just died.
(内附罚款通知单 警告)
(局长 克劳德·惠兰)
进来
Come in.
看到温特斯驾车闯入
...shows that Winters drove into the venue--
克劳德 我有 戴安娜 太感谢你了
Claude, I've got s-Diana, thank you so much for this.
这是我第一次参加 政府危机应对委员会会议
It'll be my first COBRA meeting, so I was wondering
所以我想问 你能不能跟我说说会议大致内容
if you might be able to give me a rundown of what to expect?
好 可以 我 拜托了 如果你不介意的话
Okay. Yep. Well, I'm-Please, if you wouldn't mind.
我最近很忙 所以 对 是的
I've got a lot going on, so... Right. Yes.
我就只挑重点说了 可以吗
...I'll just stick to the headlines, if that's all right.
当然 有劳了
Sure, if you wouldn't mind.
要言简意赅 言简意赅
Keep it short but dense. Short, dense.
强调人工情报的缺陷
Stress the frailty of HUMINT.
别怕说不知道
Don't be afraid to say you don't know,
别说任何无法反覆验证的东西
don't say anything that can't be triple-sourced,
别告诉他们任何你不希望泄露的事
and don't tell them anything you don't want leaked.
好 一定 你可以无视国防部部长
Yes, of course. You can ignore the Defense Secretary,
他只会想方设法削弱你 以提升军方情报处的地位
he'll only want to undermine you to boost the standing of military intelligence.
我还必须警告你 如果首相反对你的任何提议
And I have to warn you, if the PM objects to anything you suggest,
内政大臣就会落井下石
the Home Secretary will put the boot in,
即使她刚刚赞同了你所有的话
even though she's agreed to everything you have just said,
但 你会没事的 好 谢谢
but-I mean, you'll be fine. Yeah, but thanks--
但我是来通知你 又有一个人死了
But I came to tell you that there's been another death.
什么 又有炸弹袭击
What, another bomb?
不
No, no.
是枪击案 和炸弹袭击事件无关
A shooting. Unrelated.
但受害人是一名特工 不
But the victim is an agent. Oh, no.
瑞弗·卡特怀特 被他爷爷大卫·卡特怀特击毙
River Cartwright, shot by his grandfather, David Cartwright.
大卫·卡特怀特
David Cartwright?
但他不是我们最厉害的特工吗
But he was supposed to be one of our finest, wasn't he?
我是从没见过他啦 但是
I mean, I never met him, but--
不好意思 他为什么要枪杀亲孙子
I'm sorry, why on earth did he shoot his grandson?
显然他误把他当成闯入者了 但弗莱特控制了调查
Apparently he mistook him for an intruder, but Flyte's got it locked down.
好 对了 你觉得她怎么样
Right. How's she working out for you?
很好 是了 我知道她不是你选的
Good. Yes. I know she wasn't your choice.
她是我选的
She was my choice.
只不过她选的条件是你的
It was the terms of her choosing that were yours.
我觉得你会看到 招个外人有什么好处的 戴安娜
Well, I think you'll see the benefits of bringing in an outsider, Diana.
她不受任何内部政治的影响
I mean, she's unswayed by any internal politics,
这些都有助于她的可信度
all helps with the accountability drive, you know?
不要把卡特怀特的事公开
Let's not share this Cartwright incident with the public.
在找到大卫前不要 我们知道发生了什么
Not until we've found David and we know what the hell happened.
好的 没错 我能明白其中道理 真是悲剧 戴安娜
Yeah. No, I can see the sense in that. Tragic. Diana?
是
Yep.
我在想 你会不会
Was just wondering-Just wondering whether you might
希望替我去参加 这个政府危机应对委员会会议
prefer to attend this COBRA meeting rather than me?
这是局长的职责
That's a First Desk duty.
大家都说 你在接替蒂尔尼期间
But by all accounts, you did such a sterling job
做得非常出色
filling in after Tearney.
鉴于目前的严峻形势 再加上你显然经验丰富
Given the gravity of the situation and obviously your experience,
我认为也许你去出席 他们会自在得多
I think they'd be a lot more comfortable, you know, with you being present
回头你再向我汇报 好吗
and reporting back to me. Yes?
当然
Absolutely.
是吗 你答应了 这 太好了 是的 你说什么都行
Yes? Is that okay? Is it o-Great. Yes. Yep. Anything you say.
非常感谢 谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
好了
Right.
你为什么炸韦斯特艾克斯
Why did you bomb Westacres?
你的组织里有多少人
How many are in your network?
下一个目标是什么
What is the next target?
嘿
Hey.
下一个目标是什么
What is the next target?
这就是让嫌疑人招供的方法 让我去审问即可
That's how you get a suspect to talk. Just put me in a room with them.
如果真有事瞒着你 我可以坚持更久的
I could've held out longer if I was actually holding something from you.
不 所有人都有扛不住的时候 我坚持了多久
No, everyone's got a breaking point. What was mine?
七秒 就七秒
Seven seconds. Is that all?
好了 给钱 见鬼
Right. Pay up. Fuck's sake.
真好 200个
Lovely. 200.
行 好
Yeah, all right.
现在我知道是什么体验了 我觉得我能坚持一分钟
Now I know what it's like, I reckon I could do a full minute.
是啊 真的
Yeah. Yeah.
这里到底怎么了 漏水了吗
What on earth's been going on here? Do we have a leak?
没有 他给我用水刑来着
No. He's been waterboarding me.
为什么
Why?
打赌 曲别针
For a bet. Paper clips.
曲别针是他的戒赌“镇静剂”
Paper clips are his gambling methadone.
这个办公室已经够乱的了
This office is in enough of a state already.
一定要把头发擦干 亲爱的
Do dry your hair, dear.
当年在总部
You know, back at the Park,
我是“数据库女王”的办公桌分配员之一
I was one of the Desk Allocators to the Queens of the Database.
你说过了
You have mentioned it.
我依然不知道那是什么意思
Still not sure what it means.
意思就是我坐在所有部门主管的对面
It means that I was across the management of every office.
我知道谁什么时候在做什么
I knew who was doing what, when.
我觉得管理这地方更具挑战
And I find running this place more of a challenge.
你们打算什么时候把圣诞装饰收起来
When are you going to pack up the Christmas decorations?
我们抛硬币决定了 雪莉会收
We flipped for it. Shirley's gonna do it.
才不是 三局两胜
No, I'm not. Best of three.
趁还没给我们惹上霉运 快把饰品收好
Well, just pack them up before you bring us bad luck.
我们的运气已经不能更霉了
Our luck can't get any worse.
该死
Blast.
我把这些上周的文件退给你们
I'm giving you these back from last week.
怎么 是议会收到的噪音投诉清单
What, the list of noise complaints to councils?
这些需要按日期排序 是
They need to be in date order. Right.
好吧 凯瑟琳要求 这种文件按投诉数量分类 所以
Right, well, Catherine wanted things like this grouped by number of complaints, so...
凯瑟琳不在这里 对吗
Catherine's not here, is she?
随便啦
Whatever.
我们怎么做都没意义
Pointless however we do it.
早上好 JK 小心脚下
Morning, JK. Do watch your footing.
还是你喜欢被称为科
Would you prefer Coe?
科先生
Mr. Coe?
他说过话吗 一个字也没说过
Has he said anything yet? Not a word.
说实话 我对他这个状态感到很开心
Which, to be honest with you, I'm pretty happy about.
他常常做这个动作
He just does this?
在工作间隙就做 对 所以请赶快给他点活干吧
In between work, yeah, so please give him some work quick.
1.95镑
1.95.
(恶魔的心态)
什么人会炸满是顾客的购物中心啊
What kind of person blows up a shopping center full of people?
让人不禁去想下一个目标是什么
Makes you wonder what's next.
是 下一个是佳发蛋糕
Yes. Jaffa Cakes. That's what's next.
再来点我可舒适
And some Alka-Seltzer.
给 谢谢
There you go. Cheers.
你们摧毁了我
You have crushed me.
对我施暴
Wreaked violence upon me.
只有现在我才能得到自由
Only now will I be free.
两分钟后抵达
Two minutes out.
我被你们的系统囚禁多年 你们将为此付出代价
You will suffer for the years I spent imprisoned by your system.
上帝自有安排 我不会是最后一个
God willing, I will not be the last.
你们很快会从我兄弟们那里听到消息 怎么样
You will hear from my brothers soon. Well?
兰姆确认了尸体就是瑞弗·卡特怀特
Lamb identified the body as River Cartwright.
那就确定了
That's confirmed, then?
兰姆给你惹麻烦了吗
Lamb give you any trouble?
我之前对付过兰姆这样的男人
I've dealt with men like Lamb before.
我觉得你没有
I don't think you have.
大卫在哪 依然下落不明
Where's David? Still missing.
一位邻居听到半夜时有汽车驶离
A neighbor heard a car drive off in the middle of the night.
可恶的卡特怀特一家
Those bloody Cartwrights.
他们为什么 非要在我们忙不过来时搞这些
Why do they have to do this when we're stretched so thin?
找到老卡特怀特
Find Cartwright senior.
我不是该调查韦斯特艾克斯案
Shouldn't I be on Westacres?
我听说你们追踪到了 炸弹袭击者所在的公寓
I heard you traced the bomber back to a flat.
此刻正有一支武装小队突袭那里
There's an armed unit going in right now.
我要你去查卡特怀特谋杀案
I want you on the Cartwright murder.
两分钟后抵达 长官 有人进出公寓吗
Two minutes out, ma'am. Has anyone been in or out of the flat?
我们开始监视后还没有
Not since we've had eyes on it.
长官 这是温特斯 昨天下午1点刚过时出门的画面
Ma'am, this is Winters setting out just after 1:00 p.m. yesterday.
我们从今天凌晨4点就开始监视了 无人机也已升空
We've been on it since 4:00 a.m. today. Our drones are up.
窗帘都拉上了 所以我们无法确定
Curtains are drawn, so we can't be certain,
但据我们所知 那里没有其他人
but as far as we know, there's no one else in there.
这不代表里面没人 也许有共犯
Doesn't mean there isn't. Might be accomplices.
把那些小孩撤离
Move those children.
好 把那些小孩撤离
Okay. Move those children.
嗨 抱歉 我迟到了
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
后面有动静吗
Any activity at the back?
还是没有 长官
Still nothing, ma'am.
行动
Proceed.
警察 阿尔法1队进入大楼
Police! Alpha-1 entering the premises.
开门了 警察
Opening! Police!
安全
Clear.
安全 安全
Clear. Clear.
安全
Clear.
安全 安全
Clear! Clear!
安全
Clear.
他活得像个和尚
He lived like a monk.
公寓安全 长官
The flat's clear, ma'am.
这里没什么东西
There's not much to go on here.
让鉴证科的人过去 我要把那公寓翻个底朝天
Get forensics in there. I want every inch of that flat turned over.
明白
Understood.
好 兄弟们 让白大褂来搞科学调查吧
Right, boys, let's let the white coats in here to do their science.
长官
Sir.
找到一本护照
I found a passport.
和他用来租车的身份一致
It's the same ID he used to hire the car.
(罗伯特迈克尔温特斯 英国公民)
他没有隐藏身份
He wasn't hiding himself.
因为他知道自己要死了
Because he knew he was gonna die.
科学专家来了
Here come the boffins.
希望你们这些野蛮人没有把这里搞乱
Hope you animals haven't trashed the place.
没什么可搞乱的
Nothing to trash.
彻查整个公寓 有些多余的衣物 靴子 一个睡袋
Swept the whole flat, some spare clothes, boots, sleeping bag.
大概就这些 对
That's about it, yeah.
走吧 滚蛋
Go on then. Fuck off.
给这里来点光线吧
Let's shed some light on this place.
该死
Shit.
出什么事了
What just happened?
我 快回答
I-Come on.
好像有炸弹陷阱 长官 老天 什么
I think there was a booby trap, ma'am. Jesus Christ. What?
长官 三人死亡 见鬼
Ma'am, three dead... Oh, fuck.
可能有更多人受伤
...possibly more injured.
把人撤出来 封锁区域
Get them out. Lock it down.
疏散整个街区 派一个新小队去
Evacuate the entire block, and get a new team in.
我们必须弄清有没有第二个放炸弹的人
We need to know if there's a second bomber.
是 长官
Yes, ma'am.
见鬼 这真是一场灾难
Oh, fuck. This is a disaster.
彻头彻尾的灾难
Absolute bloody disaster.
克劳德
Claude.
Claude?
抱歉 我从没见过这种事
I'm sorry. I've just never seen anything quite like this
发生在我眼前 我 是 但你必须承担责任
in front of my own eyes before, so I-Yeah, but you need to shoulder it.
对 你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
我最好再向首相汇报一下 发表一份声明
I suppose I better update the PM again and issue a statement.
不 你必须先通知家属
No. You have to tell the families first.
他们不能从新闻上得知此事
They can't find out about this on the news.
当然
Of course.
我不知道自己刚才 谢谢你 戴安娜 你太可靠了
I don't know what I was-Thank you, Diana. You're a real rock.
情况更新
Where's my update?
正在疏散楼里的人 长官
Evacuating the building now, ma'am.
真是一团糟
What a mess.
罗迪里克 在
Roderick? Yeah?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
拿走卡特怀特的电脑
Taking Cartwright's computer.
为什么
Why?
因为他死了
Because he's dead.
什么 怎么了
What? What's going on?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
罗迪说瑞弗死了
Roddy just said that River's dead.
这玩笑不好笑 何
Sick joke, Ho.
不是玩笑 是事实
It's not a joke. It's a fact.
你怎么知道的 兰姆告诉我的
How would you know? Lamb told me.
兰姆告诉你什么
Lamb told you what?
这里是什么情况
What's going on in here?
卡特怀特死了
Cartwright's dead.
什么叫他死了 哈哈 很好笑
What do you mean he's dead? Very funny.
兰姆告诉我说卡特怀特死了
Lamb told me Cartwright's dead.
“我会晚点进办公室
"Will be late in.
昨晚通宵鉴定卡特怀特的尸体”
Up all night identifying Cartwright's body."
一定是玩笑 拜托 什么 在哪 怎么回事
It's got to be a windup. Come on. What? Where? What?
他一定在笑呢
He must be having a laugh.
这根本说不通啊 你跟兰姆说过话吗
This doesn't make any sense. Have you spoken to Lamb?
没有 所以
No. So--
什 你认为他死了 但你要偷他的电脑
Wha-So you think he's dead, but you nick his computer?
这不叫偷他的电脑 他死了
I'm not nicking his computer. He's dead.
任务日志上说大卫·卡特怀特家有枪击报告
Duty log says shots reported at David Cartwright's.
发现尸体
Body found.
我的天
Oh, my God.
该死 这都怪我
Oh, shit. This is my fault.
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 我叫他去的 去哪
Oh, my God. I told him to go. Go where?
我叫他去看看爷爷 他爷爷开枪把他打死了
I told him to go and see his grandfather, and his grandfather fucking shot him.
见鬼 这不是真的 什么
Fuck. Tell me this isn't true. What?
竟然又发生了
Tell me this is not happening again.
不 怎么又出这种事啊 我们甚至还不了解情况
No, this is not happening again. We don't even know the circumstances.
我们知道他死了 不是吗
We know he's dead, don't we?
我们还需要了解什么 他死了
What else do we need to know? He's dead.
说个好消息吧 我有女朋友了
Well, in happier news, I have a girlfriend.
你这个王八蛋
You're a fucking prick!
路易莎
Loui-Louisa!
好痛
Fuck!
心平气和地接受现实吧 你错过机会了
Make your peace. You missed your chance.
伦敦反恐警察和安全部门确认
Counterterrorism police and the security service
他们在追查
in London have confirmed they are following
马修阿姆罗利瓦拉 继续调查
all potential leads as the investigation into the bombing
韦斯特艾克斯购物中心爆炸案
of the Westacres Shopping Center continues.
然而一位发言人证实 他们不知道罗伯特·温特斯
Whilst a spokesperson confirmed they don't know how Robert Winters
是如何获取他所使用的装置所需原料的
acquired the ingredients for the device he used,
据了解 居民们
it's understood that residents...
一直在配合警方询问
...have been assisting police with their inquiries.
同时 25岁的杰克·沃顿
Meanwhile 25-year-old Jack Wharton
是最新公布姓名的袭击受害者
is the latest victim killed in the attack to be named.
据报道 他的兄弟在爆炸中受伤
His brother was reportedly injured by the blast.
至此 全部23名爆炸案遇难者的身份
This means that all the 23 people who died
都已经确定
in the bombing have now been identified.
今早 武装警察巡逻几条主要
This morning, armed police patrolled several major...
杰克逊 你想怎样
Jackson, what do you want?
这个欢迎很热烈啊 你可以加点感情进去的
That's a nice welcome. You could have put some feeling into it.
我加了 只不过不是你想要的那种
I did, just not the kind you were hoping for.
打算邀请我进来吗 不打算
Gonna invite me in? No.
那我强行进来呢
Mind if I come in anyway?
我带了早餐来
I brought breakfast.
我吃过了 而且那不叫早餐
I've already eaten, and that's not a breakfast.
那喝一杯如何
How about a drink then?
就算对你来说 现在喝也早了点
Bit early, even for you.
我是说喝一杯水
I meant a glass of water.
你来干吗
So, why are you here?
就不能来看看老朋友
Can't drop in on an old friend?
不太可能 这么说也不对
Unlikely and inaccurate.
我刚刚鉴定完瑞弗·卡特怀特的尸体
I've just come from identifying River Cartwright's body.
我想第一个告诉你
I wanted you to be the first to know.
看吧 瞧 早餐 里面有橙子呢
There, you see? Look, breakfast. Got orange in it.
水果 有益健康 瑞弗 怎么会
Fruit. Healthy. River? How?
胸口和脸部中枪
Bullet to the chest and a bullet to the face.
整个讨人厌的表情都没了
Literally wiped the annoying look off it.
你听了都没反应吗 这就是我的反应
Aren't you going to respond? This is me responding.
在哪发生的
Where did it happen?
洗手间里
In the bathroom.
跟当年一样 是吧
Just like old times, eh?
你打算告诉其他人吗
And will you tell the others?
我给何发了条短信
Well, I sent a text to Ho.
我想他现在应该已经告诉大家了
I expect he'd have spread the word around by now.
你发了条短信
You sent a text?
我可没打算发推文
Well, I wasn't gonna tweet it.
老天 斯坦迪什 人命关天啊
Jesus Christ, Standish, a man died.
你知道这消息 会给路易莎带来多大打击吗
You know what this news will do to Louisa?
所以我才发给何 我很讲究策略的
That's why I sent it to Ho. I know how to be tactful.
那么 既然你已经告诉我 这个坏消息了 你可以走了
So-Well, now that you've told me this terrible news, y-feel free to leave.
能看出来 你很忙
I can see you're busy.
你就不问问是谁的洗手间吗 谁的
Aren't you gonna ask whose bathroom? Whose bathroom?
抱歉 只能告诉需要知道的人
Sorry, need-to-know.
你很开心吧
You're enjoying this.
能喝杯水就更开心了
Well, I'd enjoy it more with a glass of water.
你知道通宵不睡的人有多缺水
You know how dehydrated you get after an all-nighter.
老天
For God's sake.
你一个人住
Are you alone?
对 我该先问问的
Yeah, I should have asked.
我看起来像有伴的样子
Do I look like I have company?
好吧 我必须问的
Yeah. Well, I had to ask, you know.
有些污名可不好洗刷 你应该知道
It's hard to shake off a reputation. Well, you should know.
你认识的每一个人都认为你是个大混蛋
I mean, everyone you've ever met has pegged you as an utter bastard.
但我不用受你气了 因为我辞职了 记得吗
But I don't have to put up with you anymore because I quit. Remember?
至少我尝试辞职了 我给人事部写了三封同样的信
Well, I tried to. I've written the same letter to HR three times.
是 我知道 他们总把信转发给我
Yeah, I know. They keep forwarding it to me.
文件总得有人批嘛
Something about ratifying the paperwork.
老天 兰姆 问题到底出在哪
For God's sake, Lamb. What's the problem?
你多年来一直刺激我 然后我终于做了让你如愿以偿的事
I mean, you spent years goading me, and then I finally did what you wanted.
在该死的辞职信上签字啊 让我继续过我的人生
Just sign the damn papers, and let me get on with my life.
我想确保你了解自己的心意
I wanna make sure you know your own mind.
对 想像一下
Right, imagine how I'd feel
如果你后悔不已 酒瘾复发 我该有多难受
if you wound up full of regret and had a relapse.
我可不想背负这种良心债
I wouldn't want that on my conscience,
你会整天以泪洗面 借酒消愁
you getting all weepy and hitting the bottle.
人们说酒鬼都在找借口
Now, they say drunks are just looking for an excuse.
我不怪你 这是一种病
I'm not blaming you, it's a disease.
对了 是他爷爷的
It was his grandfather's, by the way.
什么
What?
他爷爷的洗手间 不是因为你问我才说的
His grandfather's bathroom, not that you asked.
你也没问是谁
You also didn't ask who.
什么谁 谁枪杀了瑞弗
Who what? Who shot River.
因为你和我一样 知道他还活着
Because, like me, you know he's alive.
别耍花样了
So stop playing games.
你刚刚告诉我说 你确认是他的尸体
You've just told me you'd identified his body.
是啊 你对当时的情况表现得非常不在意
Yeah, and you were remarkably incurious about the circumstances.
我惊呆了 好吗
I'm in shock, okay.
你惊讶的是我来了 而不是
You're in shock at me being here, but you're not in shock
瑞弗还活着 因为你见过他
at the idea of River being alive because you've seen him.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
一派胡言 才不是
That's absolute rubbish. No, don't.
拜托 斯坦迪什 不
Please, Standish. No--
你很不擅长这一套
You're no good at this.
再说了
And besides...
他的车就停在外面
his car's outside.
是的 好吧 他来过
Yes. Okay. He was here,
但现在不在这里了 好 这还差不多
but he's not here anymore. All right, that's better.
好了 请别装了
Now, please don't pretend
你一定把那个老混蛋藏在卧室了
you haven't got the old bastard stashed away in the bedroom.
杰克逊 瑞弗叫我保护他
Jackson. River asked me to protect him.
满意了
Happy now?
你是了解我的
You know me.
知道我什么时候不是满心欢喜
When am I not full of joie de fucking vivre.
很好 你现在就从我的卧室里出去吧
Good. Well, perhaps you could leave my bedroom now.
嘿
Hey!
哥们
Mate.
瑞弗在哪
Where's River?
(巴黎德士)
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
还有多久到
How much longer?
没多远了
We aren't far now.
字幕翻译 吴梦熊